Friends, if you have to purchase a medical policy
and in future, don't worry, if any such
problem arises and
you get hospitalized, then friends, if
you watch this video, then at least you will not face any problem in the future.
Friends, if we talk about purchasing any policy, the
first thing
you have to look at is the policy document i.e. policy
wording. You should read the policy wording properly,
right, it will take you a little time,
but friends, if you have to purchase a medical policy
and in future, don't worry, if any such
problem arises and you get
hospitalized, then at least
you should
not face any problem in the hospital, right, so what things should
you keep in mind, what are the things that
while taking a policy, it is very important for you to read all
its documents, etc., their terms, what are all those
things,
right, so friends, if you watch this video, then at least
you will not face any problem in the future. So, I would
like to tell you in some points, what are the
most important things for you to keep in mind,
friends, if we talk about any policy,
if we  When you make a purchase, the first thing
you have to look at is the policy document, i.e.,
policy wording. Policy wording is
such a thing in which you will get to know all the limits,
from the capping of room rent to any other limit,
like the capping has been done, the payment has been made, everything is mentioned
on the policy document, i.e., all the
things are mentioned in the policy wording. What happens sometimes is
that some agents, in
order to complete their targets,
either when you go to the bank, there will be a
representative, even if you
want to make a purchase online, then the company
representative at least may hide
that thing from you there,
or he may hide something from you, so that
you may face some problem in the future. So,
if you
read the policy wording properly, it will take some
time, but if you
read it properly, then you will come to know that
these things will not be covered in the future,
right, so you already have a waiting
period, right, it is already there.
You will have awareness and
you will not face any problem in the future. Now
comes the matter of where to find the policy wording. Right,
policy wording. If we look at any
insurance company, there is a policy wording on their website. If
you go to the plan you want to purchase, then the
policy wording will be there. As soon as you click on it,
you can download the policy wording.
After that, it will take some time.
You should read it properly. Or
you can tell the agent from whom you want to buy the policy, brother, please
send me the policy wording. I will first
read the policy wording. After that, I will take a
decision. Right,
we have got the policy wording. So, the first thing we need to look at in the policy wording is what is
important to look at. The second thing that is important to look at is
exclusions. What things are
excluded? There is one exclusion, right, there is a temporary
exclusion,
like cataract, hernia, stone, there is a
planning surgery, like what is called
specific illness waiting period, which is of two
years, right, but there are some things like this.
Basically, they come under your permanent
exclusions, so you should read that too. There might be some
disease which the
companies do not cover, that is, it is
in the permanent exclusion, but
in the future, if there is any such disease or any such problem, then
in the future,
you will not get the claim after going to the hospital. So, it is
very important for you to read the permanent exclusions as well.
All the things are
available within the policy wording itself.
After that, if we come to the third number,
what is the third number, what is your application form as of today? What
we used to do earlier was to
fill the form physically. Right, in the physical form,
do you have any pre-existing disease, have you undergone
any surgery, are you
on any medication right now? So, all these questions are
basically a very long
question. They are either agents or
representatives. Basically, they
tick both, right, but it is
very important for you to check whether there is any pre-existing
disease and the agents have not done that to
complete their target, or the
representative has not done the target.
In the process of completing it, your policy was issued and
in the future you kept taking the claim and the company
said that you already had a disease, you have already
ticked it, no, right then
your claim can be rejected, so
if the proposal form is filled online also then
you should check completely whether you have any
disease, if it is mentioned in it or not,
if it is mentioned, you must have mentioned it properly, then
you will not face any such problem in the future,
right, coming at number four
is check cashless and blacklisted
hospitals, right, now cashless hospital,
suppose that in the city where you live,
if you
find a cashless hospital nearby, then
you will not face any such problem,
most of the companies basically cover it,
but there are some companies which
still have very less network hospitals,
so first of all you have to check whether a
network hospital is
available in your vicinity or not, along with this, it is
also important for you to check
whether there is a blacklisted hospital near you, it is a
big hospital but the companies have
blacklisted it.  If you have kept it then it is
very important for you to visit a blacklisted hospital as well. The
next thing we will do is disclose the
pre-existing disease. Right, if
you disclose your pre-existing disease
and the company issues
your policy without loading or waiting period,
then in future
you can say 100% that your claim will be approved. You do
not need anyone's support.
Your claim will be 100% approved. Right, that is why it is
very important for you to mention the material facts, that is, whatever your things are, they should be proper in the proposal form of the insurance company. So
you must keep this thing in mind. Right, friends, the
next point that comes in it is
portability. Now
in cases of portability, suppose you are
running a policy in some other company. Right, you have run it for 3 years,
5 years, right,
you are shifting to another company. Now
what did that company do? What was your claim?
You had taken the claim in any year, but it has happened
that your representative did not take your claim.  The
agents did not mention those details. Your
policy has been running for 10 years but there must be some
conditions which have been running for 10 years
but you did not enter the proper
details of that policy which you are shifting to the company,
right,
so here also you may face problems
and difficulties in the future, so at the time of portability, it is
very important for you to check the portability properly, you should
check the portability form properly, whether you are getting the portability benefit for the number of years your
policy has been running
or not, many companies,
if you have added Nocal Bonus in that company, then
they also transfer the Nocal Bonus,
so it is important for you to check that too whether it is getting
transferred or not, right,
after that friends, the basic
details which come are done, it is very important for you to fill the basic details, there should
not be any mistake in your name, right, your
contact number, point of contact number,
emergency contact number, that is very important, suppose for
your claim, for your
pre-approval,  For example, if you go to a TPA
for pre-approval of a hospital, then
after going there your mobile
number should be proper. If
your agents have entered their mobile number, then the
messages etc. that will
go to the agents, it is very important for you to mention your complete email ID and mobile number properly
in your proposal form so that in
future, in emergency times, you
can directly receive SMS from the company. Suppose
you get admitted, right, if there is
any requirement in the TPA, then immediately a
message will come on your mobile, right, you
can go there and say, brother, please
send this document again. So, your
proper information, normal
information, your mobile number, email ID,
contact, everything, it is very important for you to mention it properly in the proposal form.
So friends, this was some information which is
very important for you to pay attention while taking the policy.
If you do that carefully, then at least
in future you will
not face any problem in the claim. Video is very
important for your near and dear
friend circle.  If you like the video, please do like it so that
we get motivation from your like.
Right friends, if you are not subscribed to the channel, then do so
so that in the future
you will keep getting such latest information through this channel.
If you are
thinking of purchasing an insurance policy,
purchasing the best health insurance is a
very tough task. It takes you eight to 10
hours to search and research the policy and
find it for yourself. We have one of the
best experts, IRD registered authorized
advisors, you
can book a free consultation, who will
find a proper and customized product for you from the market so that
you do not face any problem in the future at the time of claim.
If you are an insurance agent
or you want to make your career in insurance,
you
want to serve people by selling health insurance, then also
you can join us. You will be happy to know that we
recruit agents on an all India level basis, we
train the agents and in health insurance
they serve the best of the people, from
good to the best.  I am
working today, I am an MDRT Achiever
Advisor, we have trained many people
and today we are
training them and motivating them,
right, if you want to join us,
you can whatsapp us on web,
Jai Hind, Vande Mataram